SERGIO IGNACIO CHAVEZ LAZO

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Researcher with a Professional Degree in Social Sciences with mention in Sociology of the Pontifical Catholic University of Peru. Experience in quantitative and qualitative research work. I consider myself a person with discipline, engage with teamwork and focus on the results.

EDUCATION

Licentiate, Sociology – Academic Excellence, June 2020 Pontifical Catholic University of Peru (PUCP)

Professional specialization in Applied Statistics (180 hours) February 2021

National School of Statistics and Informatics (ENEI)

Professional Specialization in Data Science, May 2020 **IBM**

Specialization in Behavioral Economics (120 hours), December 2020

Pacific University

Specialization in Design Thinking (50 hours), October 2020 **European Graduate Institute (IEP)**

Specialization in Statistics with R – Current **Duke University**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant at Vice Rector's Office (VRI), PUCP October 2020 – Current

Responsible for supporting the VRI with the elaboration of benchmarking, visualization and systematization of PUCP research data. In addition, support the Office of Research Ethics and Scientific Integrity (OETIIC) reviewing the format of the projects.

Member of the Decision Lab research team, Aug 2020 – Current

Research Team of Public Policies Prospective - PUCP

Member of the research team that tries to implement the behavioral science approach to the public policies development and academic documentation.

CONTACT

Address: Calle del Perú 401 – Yanahuara, Arequipa

Phone: (+51) 958582763

Email:

sergio.chavezl@pucp.edu.pe

SKILLS

- Research abilities
- Quantitative and qualitative analysis
- Data analysis Tools
- Information visualization and presentation

LANGUAGES

- English Advanced (TOEFL Score: 108)
- Portuguese Intermediate

SOFTWARE

- SPSS
- Python
- SQL
- STATA
- R Studio
- Power BI
- Excel Data Model

Teacher Assistant of the courses: "Statistics for sociological analysis 1" and "Methodology of quantitative research" at the Pontifical Catholic University of Peru

August 2021 - Current

Responsible for design and teaching courses with a quantitative approach during practice hours.

Assistant in the elaboration of "Young People Study 2019 – SM Foundation" supporting the group "Ages of Life and Education (EVE)" – April 2021 to September 2021

Responsible for database management to create tables, graphics and statistical analysis requested by authors.

Research Assistant at PUCP, August 2020 to December 2020 CISEPA - PUCP

Assistant of Professor Robin Cavagnoud, in charge of documentation, organization and graphic design of information about the sociodemographic transition in Peru from 1961 up to present.

Intern in the area of Project Coordination, March 2018 to December 2019

Public Opinion Institute - PUCP

Member of the group elaborating proposals, collecting information, processing data and analysis of qualitative and quantitative results of different consulting offices of social, business and public opinion areas.

Assistant in Elaboration of NNA Action Plan, May 2020 to June 2020 Independent

Support a consulting office designated by the Ministry of Women and Vulnerable Population (MIMP) to elaborate the Action Plan to reduce violence against children and adolescents (NNA). Responsible for searching the indicators and literature to assemble the document, the elaboration and systematization of virtual survey applied to specialists in the topic.

Research Assistant, July 2020 to August 2020 CUANTI

Part of the team in charge of proposing teaching methodologies for the quantitative and qualitative research advising offices.

VOLUNTARY WORK AND HOBBIES

 Outstanding Athlete (2017 – Current). Passionate for strength sports since 2017. I was a junior national champion and called to participate in the South America tournament of 2019 in Uruguay.

- Survey Monkey
- Data Studio

ACADEMIC MERITS

- Academic Excellence: First place in the graduating class of the specialty in Sociology, School of Social Sciences in the 2019-2 academic semester.
- Winner of the Support Program for Thesis Development of the Licentiate Degree.
- Winner of the Research Monograph Contest 2018 of the School of Social Sciences.
- Finalist of the "First Step" Contest for innovative projects of the University of Lima.
- Co-author of workbook entitled: "Influence of associativity in productive opportunities: Case of 4 agricultural and livestock associations in Moquegua" (Bobadilla, et al. 2019).
- Author of the article: "Religion and catholic approval of the political intervention of the Churches and its leaders in Peru". (Chavez, 2019) published in *La Colmena* magazine.
- Thesis for the obtention of Licentiate Degree passed by unanimous vote and a qualification of outstanding

REFERENCES

Ledda Naravez – Head of Project Areas of the Public Opinion Institute at PUCP.

Contact: narvaez.lm@pucp.edu.pe – (+51) 990299097

- Founder Member of RC Barbell (2018 Current).
 Athletes team that wants to promote powerlifting by organizing training and spreading information based on scientific research of sport science.
- Stand-Up Comedy Workshop Student of the Comedy Institute (August 2021 – Current). I started to study and practice stand comedy taught by Omar Jeffrey and Ronal Balmaceda.
- "Healthy PUCP" Volunteer (2019). Part of the volunteer team in charge of promoting health habits at PUCP university community. During that time, I organized along with 3 partners in order to organize a campaign to raise awareness about the massive alcohol consumption.
- "Out of the Cage" Project (2011 2013). Member of a group of students of San Jose de Arequipa High School that evaluated the needs of the Maca community at Valle del Colca, and elaborated a support plan to carry out.

CERTIFICATES

- CISEPA: Workshop: Introduction to Impact Evaluation (July 2017)
- CISEPA: Workshop: Strategic Planning for Research Project Management (July 2018)
- School of Social Sciences: Workshop: Elaboration of Social Baseline (September 2018)
- La Colmena Magazine: Workshop: Applied Statistics for Social Sciences (October 2019)
- Healthy PUCP: Workshop: "Life Skills" (January 2020)
- National School of Statistics and Informatics: Course "Basic STATA" (February 2020)
- Microsoft: Virtual course "Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Excel" (April 2020)
- Microsoft: Virtual course "Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI" (May 2020)
- Harvard University: Virtual course "The Health Effects of Climate Change" (June 2020)
- Toronto University: Virtual Course "Behavioral Economics in Action" (June 2020)
- Inter-American Development Bank (IDB): "Project Management for Development" (September 2020)
- PUCP: Training course in Machine Learning for Social Sciences (February 2021)

Robin Cavagnoud – Director of the Master Program in Sociology at PUCP and Director of the Debates in Sociology magazine
Contact: rcavagnoud@pucp.pe – (+51) 997068421